<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="101" moduleid="5884" modulename="book" contextid="19754">
  <book id="101">
    <name>Conclusion</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;session 1&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1462567882</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1462568710</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="792">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of two guiding questions</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of two guiding questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll finish up this course by reviewing our two guiding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our two guiding questions were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;What does it mean for an adult with LD to be self-determined?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;What can adult service providers do to promote &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; for adults with LD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463422236</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="793">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of guiding question #1</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of guiding question #1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In exploring guiding question number one, we began by asking you about a time in your life when &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; played a role. We then discussed importance of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; for a person with LD, and examined six factors that affect an individual’s ability to be self-determined. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463422273</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="794">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review of guiding question #2</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review of guiding question #2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to our second guiding question, we gathered ideas for adult service providers wishing to promote &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; for adults with LD. We then asked you to prioritize at least two of the six factors for your learners, and to make a plan to implement at least one idea or strategy to address those factors in your adult education practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope you will be able to use this information to enable individuals with LD to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;overcome challenges they face and assume greater control over their lives;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve their educational goals; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improve their confidence in themselves and their abilities. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/SD%20triumphant.png" width="550" height="411" alt="Photo of a young woman with arms in the air – triumphant." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463422362</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="795">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Participate in the forum discussions</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Participate in the forum discussions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing Learning to Achieve’s &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Self-Determination&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/i&gt;course&lt;em&gt;!&lt;/em&gt; We encourage you to stay involved in the LINCS Community and the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/disabilities-adult-education" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; as you strive to incorporate strategies for helping adults with LD to develop &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt;. We encourage you to discuss and apply your newly acquired knowledge and learn about others' experiences in teaching and supporting adults with LD.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463422428</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="796">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Complete the evaluation and print your certificate</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Complete the &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;evaluation&lt;/span&gt; and print your certificate&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concludes the &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Self-Determination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt; course. We would like to thank the individuals and organizations who generously contributed to the design and development of this course:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINCS Regional Professional Development Center, Region 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Center for Literacy, Education &amp;amp; Employment at the University of Tennessee, Knoxville staff Aaron Kohring, Duren Thompson, and Margy Ragsdale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National Institute for Literacy independent panel of experts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that we can maintain the quality of our courses, we ask that you take a moment to complete the&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;course evaluation. Your feedback will ensure our courses meet your needs for professional development. Thank you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="margin-bottom: 30px; margin-top: 30px;" class="graybox"&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 1em; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;Access and Print Your Certificate Anytime&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing this LINCS Learning to Achieve course, &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Self-Determination&lt;/span&gt; for Adults with Learning Disabilities. To obtain your completion certificate, simply close this window and return to the course homepage. You will find a link for the completion certificate under the Course Conclusion and Resources section header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The Literacy Information and Communication System (LINCS) Learning to Achieve course was developed by Manhattan Strategy Group, LLC for the U.S. Department of Education, Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education under Contract No. ED-VAE-14-C-0123. The opinions expressed herein do not necessarily represent the positions or policies of the U.S. Department of Education, and no official endorsement by the U.S. Department of Education should be inferred. This course is in the public domain and may be used without permission.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469734448</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>