<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="96" moduleid="5879" modulename="book" contextid="19749">
  <book id="96">
    <name>Reflecting and Readjusting</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;session 1&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1462567882</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1462568608</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="764">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Elements of reflecting and readjusting</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Elements of reflecting and readjusting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What individuals learn from successes or failures and achievements or disappointments is as important as the actual outcomes. Some individuals have difficulty understanding the role they play in their own successes and failures. Thus, the ability to reflect, analyze and develop insight into what contributes to success or failure is an important part of the learning process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elements of reflecting and readjusting include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evaluating differences between actual outcome or performance and expected outcome or performance;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;celebrating successes; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;readjusting for next time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462984652</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="765">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Questions related to reflecting and readjusting</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Questions related to reflecting and readjusting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A self-determined person can answer these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can I analyze what happened to determine what led to the outcome?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What was my role in the outcome?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What worked well and what would I do differently?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462984681</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="766">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Importance of reflecting and readjusting</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Importance of reflecting and readjusting&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For learners with LD, determining what contributes to their successes and failures can be complicated. For example, successful learners may say, “Yes, it was easy” or “The teacher gave me a break.” This type of attribution shows that they are not putting themselves into the learning equation. They are not seeing that what they did made a difference and helped them succeed. These individuals believe that they are successful because of what others do rather than because of what they do. This is a common trap for individuals with LD who do not understand their disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We want them to learn that what they do makes a difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/blonde%20girl%20thinking2.jpg" width="550" height="415" alt="Photo of a teenage girl in class with bored expression, chin leaning on hand. Text: “What was my role in the outcome?”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462984985</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="767">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify ways to help individuals with LD reflect and readjust</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify ways to help individuals with LD reflect and readjust&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this information, and your own experiences, consider what you can do as a service provider to help individuals with LD learn to reflect and readjust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please write down for yourself at least one thing you can do to support individuals with LD learn to reflect and  readjust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have finished recording your ideas, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to proceed. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462985016</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="768">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Ideas to help individuals with LD reflect and readjust</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Ideas to help individuals with LD reflect and readjust&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ideas for helping individuals with LD to reflect and readjust are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask individuals to re-examine their goals, and readjust them if they weren’t realistic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow individuals to check work or performance before completing a task;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow individuals to redo tests, assignments and tasks after receiving feedback (if possible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage individuals to recognize and celebrate their successes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to compare your ideas with those listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;Continue on to the final factor, Environment&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463428194</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>