<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="88" moduleid="5871" modulename="book" contextid="19741">
  <book id="88">
    <name>Introduction</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;intro&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1461791493</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1461958055</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="716">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Welcome to this LINCS course</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Welcome to this LINCS course&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;i&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Self-Determination for Adults with Learning Disabilities&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/i&gt;course of the Learning to Achieve Program, a research-based training on serving adults with learning disabilities. This program is brought to you by the Literacy Information and Communication System (LINCS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course was developed under the LINCS Regional Professional Development Center for Adult Education&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;PR/Award Number V191B110003, administered by the Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education, U.S. Department of Education. However, the contents do not necessarily represent the positions or policies of the Office of Career, Technical, and Adult Education or the U.S. Department of Education, and you should not assume endorsement by the Federal Government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow &lt;/b&gt;to begin.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462813636</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="717">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Join the LINCS Community and participate in course discussions</title>
        <content>&lt;h1&gt;Join the LINCS Community and participate in course discussions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;This course is designed for teachers of adult learners with learning disabilities (LD). As with all LINCS courses, this course includes opportunities to connect with other adult education practitioners interested in the field of LD. If you haven’t already done so, take a moment to register as a member of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/" style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;LINCS Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; and participate in the discussions related to this course. The discussions provide an open forum to share your thoughts, ideas, and questions with other adult education practitioners.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this course, you will have the opportunity to share your ideas and plans as you learn about&lt;span class="nolink"&gt; self-determination&lt;/span&gt; in adults with learning disabilities. This is a great opportunity to share and learn from others. We encourage you to participate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt; &lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/LINCS_CommPage_04_27.PNG" width="543" height="545" alt="screen shot of LINCS community landing page" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462813719</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="718">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Course objectives</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this course, we will explore an important attribute associated with successful adult living: &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination. &lt;/span&gt;We will examine factors that promote &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt;, as well as how &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; can be developed in educational services for individuals with learning disabilities (LD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon completion of this course, you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;explain the importance of&lt;span class="nolink"&gt; self-determination&lt;/span&gt; for a person with LD, and describe six factors that affect an individual’s ability to be self-determined; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identify how professionals working with adults with LD can support those adults in developing &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination &lt;/span&gt;to achieve their goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_____________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please allow approximately 1 hour to complete this course. However, you are free to leave the session at any time. When you exit the courseware, a bookmark is automatically placed at your last location to allow you to pick up where you left off when you return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigation: The course is divided up into several sections: &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Introduction&lt;/span&gt;, Guiding Question #1, Guiding Question #2, and Course &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/span&gt; and Resources. You may navigate through the course by using the forward arrows when available, by going back to the main course page, or via the Table of Contents on the right side of your screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462813944</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="719">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Guiding questions</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Guiding questions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will address the course objectives by working through two key guiding questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_______&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;Guiding question #1:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;What does it mean for an adult with LD to be self-determined?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;Guiding question #2:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt;What can adult service providers do to promote &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; for adults with LD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to begin our examination of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; with a definition.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462814026</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="720">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Definition of self-determination</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Definition of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to review this definition of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt;. What are some key concepts you see in this definition?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;“&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Self-determination&lt;/span&gt; is a combination of skills, knowledge and beliefs that enables a person to engage in goal-directed, self-regulated, autonomous behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;An understanding of one's strengths and limitations together with a belief in oneself as capable and effective is essential to &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt;. When acting on the basis of these skills and attitudes, individuals have greater ability to take control of their lives and assume the role of successful adults in our society.” (Field, et. al. 1998)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to compare your response to ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/SDdef-blackman.png" width="600" height="450" alt="Photo of a young man smiling." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462814067</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="721">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Key concepts in self-determination definition</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Key concepts in &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; definition&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While other answers may apply, some key concepts you may have identified include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skills;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;knowledge;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beliefs;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;autonomous behaviors; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this definition we can see that &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; can be an important factor in a happy and successful adult life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;Continue on to Self-Determination and LD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1462814176</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>