<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="99" moduleid="5882" modulename="book" contextid="19752">
  <book id="99">
    <name>Review Activities</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;session 2&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1462567882</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1462568733</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="782">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Examples from work with adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Examples from work with adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second guiding question asks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;What can adult service providers can do to &lt;b&gt;promote &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; for adults with LD?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll review the ideas generated earlier in this course and then ask you to identify what you feel are the most important ideas and which new ideas you may want to try to implement in your own practice. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463420784</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="783">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Review activity introduction</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Review activity &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;introduction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we explored each of the six factors that affect an individual’s ability to be self-determined, we asked you, as a service provider, to generate ideas on what you could do to support, instruct and encourage learners relating to each factor. In addition, we presented some of our own ideas for promoting &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; relating to each of the six areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt;Let’s review the ideas relating to each of these factors, and identify which ideas you plan to incorporate into your own work with adults with LD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Tree_normal.jpg" width="546" height="444" alt="Background image of a tree with the following labels scattered on top of it: Gain Self-Awareness; Learn to Value Yourself; Plan; Be Proactive; Reflect &amp;amp; Readjust; Environment. Graphic title: “Factors Contributing to Self-Determination.”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Label"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463421293</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="784">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Supporting individuals with LD to build self-awareness</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Supporting individuals with LD to build self-awareness&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let’s examine ideas for supporting students in building self-awareness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ideas for building self-awareness included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask individuals to self-assess their strengths and needs;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;provide specific feedback on areas of strength and need you have observed;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask individuals what they liked and disliked about a task or activity; ask individuals to predict what they will find easier and more difficult about a task, and how long they think it will take them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to review your own ideas, and those listed. Which ones do you plan to incorporate in your work? Highlight those ideas or write them on a separate sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; when you are ready to move on to the next factor. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463421341</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="785">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Supporting individuals with LD to learn to value themselves</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Supporting individuals with LD to learn to value themselves&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, let’s examine ideas for supporting students in learning to value themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ideas for supporting individuals to value themselves included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incorporate cooperative activities that allow individuals to contribute their strengths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide specific feedback about what an individual did well, emphasizing what the individual did that helped him or her be successful in the task. Prior to giving feedback, ask the individual to tell you what he or she did that contributed to success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up a system whereby participants can self-record progress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to review your own ideas, and those listed. Which ones are a priority for you to implement in your practice? Highlight those ideas or write them on a separate sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; when you are ready to move on to the next factor. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463421369</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="786">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Supporting individuals with LD to develop planning skills</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Supporting individuals with LD to develop &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;planning&lt;/span&gt; skills&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, let’s examine ideas that support students in developing skills for &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;planning&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ideas for supporting individuals to plan effectively included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support them in setting short- and long-term goals (for example, inform individuals of the objective for a class or tutoring session and have them set a goal for their learning for that session), as well as mid-range goals (such as, How many vocabulary words do you want to learn this month?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once goals are set, involve the individuals in &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;planning&lt;/span&gt; how to accomplish an assigned task, asking them to identify one or more strategies they can use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask individuals to evaluate the effectiveness of a class and tutoring session and set a plan for the next session.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to review your own ideas, and those listed. Which ones do you feel would be invaluable to your learners? Highlight those ideas or write them on a separate sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; when you are ready to move on to the next factor. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463421628</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="787">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Supporting individuals with LD to be proactive</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Supporting individuals with LD to be proactive&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, let’s examine ideas for supporting our students to take action and be proactive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some ideas for supporting individuals to be proactive include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide contextualized instruction, such as using relevant situations from participants’ lives to teach written and oral communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect possible consequences with actions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage individuals to ask questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage appropriate peer assistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help individuals identify persons who can support their goals and plan how to communicate with these persons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to review your own ideas, and those listed. Highlight the ideas for supporting individuals with LD to be proactive that you plan to incorporate in your work or write them on a separate sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; when you are ready to move on to the next factor. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463421657</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="788">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Supporting individuals with LD to reflect and readjust plans</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Supporting individuals with LD to reflect and readjust plans&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s examine ideas for supporting our learners as they reflect and readjust their plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ideas for helping individuals with LD reflect and readjust are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask individuals to re-examine their goals, and readjust them if they weren’t realistic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow individuals to redo tests, assignments and tasks after receiving feedback (if possible).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow individuals to check work or performance before completing a task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage individuals to recognize and celebrate their successes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to review your own ideas, and those listed. Which ones are a priority for your practice? Again, highlight those ideas or write them on a separate sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; when you are ready to move on to the next factor. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463421687</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="789">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Creating an environment that supports self-determination</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Creating an &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt; that supports &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, let’s review ideas for how we can create an &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt; that supports the development of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our ideas for promoting an &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt; that supports the development of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-determination&lt;/span&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide choices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that communication between service provider and learner is culturally sensitive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that the wealth of knowledge and experience that individuals bring to the &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;environment&lt;/span&gt; is valued, respected and used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to review your own ideas, and those listed. Highlight the ones you feel are critical to your student’s success in becoming self-determined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #800000;"&gt;Continue on to the Reflection Activities in the next factor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1463428782</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>